Osama Mohammed Ahmed Al-Mamari

Address: Republic of Yemen, Sana'a

Mobil: +967 779558800 E-mail: yemencoder@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/OsamaAlmamri

SUMMARY

Effective, action-oriented professional offering more than 4 years of experience in IT software development industry using Microsoft, Oracle, Java and Google technologies, based Agile methodology focusing on conceptualizing business needs and translating them into a viable technical solution, with proven track records of success in Software Engineering and develop several enterprise solutions.

EDUCATION

•	Diploma in Full Stack Web developer Road Coding Academy (720 Hours)	2019-2020
•	Bachelor of Computer Sciences Sana'a University (93.84% Excellent Honors)	2016-2019
•	Secondary School Osama Bin Zaid (91.75% Excellent Honors)	2012-2014

WORK HISTORY

•	prodigy-solutions Company Full Stack Web Developer	Oct 2021 – Until Now
•	Targets Guide Company Full Stack Web Developer	Dec 2020 – Oct 2021
•	Yemen Ministry Of Health Trainer, IT Support and Web Developer	Dec 2020 – Oct 2021
•	Soft Upgrade Company Full Stack Web Developer	Feb 2020 – Oct 2021
•	Freelancer Full Stack Web Developer	2017 – Until Now

LANGUAGE

- **Arabic** -Mother tongue
- English Good

Application Developer

2020-NOW

- Build Damage Assessment Study (DAS) of the Urban Water Supply and Sanitation Situation in Yemen

 Stage IV using Laravel PHP and MySQL for database, and Vuejs for user interfaces.
- 2. Build new (SINGLE WINDOW PROJECTS) Dashboard using Laravel PHP and MySQL for database, and Vuejs for user interfaces for ministry of Health of Yemen to manage NGOs Projects.
- 3. Build new (E-commerce Online Store) to Erum Store In USA, API & Dashboard using LARAVEL PHP and MySQL for database and Vuejs for user interfaces.
- 4. Build new (LOGISTIC SERVICES SYSTEM) for Oryx Express Company using Laravel PHP and MySQL for database, and Vuejs for user interfaces and Build Drivers and Customers Apps Using (PWA)
- 5. Build (YEMEN CORNER WEB SITE) that offer cultural and other topic in Yemen using Laravel PHP and MySQL for database.
- 6. Build (STATIC DATA) PROJECT API & Dashboard using .Net Core5 and SqlServer for database and Vuejs for user interfaces.
- 7. Build new (POS SYSTEM) for sabafon company to Manage Point of Sales, API and Dashboard using Laravel PHP and Oracle PLSQL for database, and Vuejs for user interfaces.
- 8. Participate in building (CRM AND HR SYSTEM) for grant Thornton company to manage employees' tasks in projects and attencence of employees in project site using GPS or Finger Print in Office, using Laravel PHP MySQL for database.
- 9. Build new (E-commerce Online Store) to Hlallmadi Store in UAE for solid sacrifices, API & Dashboard using LARAVEL PHP and MySQL for database.
- 10. Participate in building (HR SYSTEM) Ministry of Health using Apex and Oracle PLSQL for database.
- 11. Build new (E-COMMERCE STORE) that manage by Yemeni Women's Union Organization that Providing an Opportunity for Yemeni Women to sell handmade Products, API and Dashboard using Laravel PHP and Oracle PLSQL for database, and Vueis for user interfaces
- 12. Build new (Training and consultant site) that manage by Yemeni Women's Union Organization that Providing an Training Courses and Consultant for Women, API and Dashboard using Laravel PHP and Oracle PLSQL for database, and Vuejs for user interfaces

Application Developer

2017-2020

- 1. Build new (INSTITUTE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM) API & Dashboard using LARAVEL PHP and MySQL for database. successfully tested and sold for more than two clients. (Android &IOS app built using Flutter platform)
- 2. Build New (SHIPMENT SYSTEM) for Darba Al-Nahma that provide shipment goods between governate in Yemen, API for the android App & Dashboard using LARAVEL PHP for backend and Vuejs for Admin dashboard & MySQL for Database and using Pusher & firebase for notification
- 3. Build (Ports Management system) for registering suspects with the Corona virus Ministry of Health
- 4. Build new (E-commerce Online Store) to Mysan Store in Saudi Arabic, API & Dashboard using LARAVEL PHP and MySQL for database.

- 5. Build test site (E-COMMERCE ONLINE STORE) Dashboard using NodeJS and Mongo DB for database.
- 6. Participate in building (E-COMMERCE ONLINE STORE) to Hudud Tabook Store in Saudi Arabic, API & Dashboard using LARAVEL PHP and MySQL for database.
- 7. Participate in building new (SOCIAL NETWORKING SITE) project for staff and students of the College of Excellence for Medical and Technical Sciences
- 8. Build (ELECTRONIC KEY WEBSITE) using LARAVEL PHP and MySQL for database.

9.

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCES

Technical

- experience in building web Apps with new technologies (Vue, React, TypeScript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap) using PHP language pure or PHP frameworks such (Laravel), NodeJS or Asp .net Core.
- experience in developing relational databases using MySQL, MS-SQL Server and Oracle DBMS.
- Experience in developing non-relational databases using MongoDB, Firebase and index DB.
- experience in building notifications in apps using busher, firebase, Expo Notifications.
- understanding of the System Analyst, object oriented and design patterns concepts using Case Tools such UML/ Agile methodology.
- experience in building web sites using WordPress;
- Test sites and applications in different browsers and environment
- analyze product specifications, design implementations, write code and rapidly deliver product feature designs.
- Evaluating code to ensure it meets industry standards, is valid, is properly structured, and is compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems
- Experience with version control systems such as git, Bitbucket and GitHub
- Build Restful API and deals with JSON files

Non-Technical

- Ability to work under pressure, independently and with limited supervision
- Self-motivated and able to achieve deadlines and work independently
- interest in new technologies.
- Seek out and actively promote ideas.
- learn and test new technologies, frameworks and language
- Possibility to work remotely or from the workplace.
- Ability to self-educate.
- Able to adapt to new environments and acquire new skills very rapidly.
- Proven ability at analyzing complex problems.
- Excellent Leadership and communication skills.
- Proven success in implementing management, operations, technical and interpersonal skills to increase productivity, reliability and teamwork to benefit the company.

SKILLS MATRIX

	Skill	Last used	Years	Proficiency
	JetBrains PHPStorm IDE	Current	+5	Expert
ning	Microsoft Visual Studio (20014-2022)	Current	+5	Moderate
ramı	NetBeans PHP IDE	2018	3+	Moderate
IDE Programming Platforms	Oracle SQL Developer	2021	+2	Expert
DE P	Oracle JDeveloper 11	2021	+2	Good
	Visual Studio Code	Current	+3	Expert
	MySQL (7,8)	Current	+5	Expert
	MongoDB	2020	+1	Good
NIS I	Microsoft SQL Server (2005,2008,2014,2016)	Current	+2	Good
DBMS	Oracle 11g,12g & PL-SQL	2021	+3	Good
	PostgreSQL DB	Current	+1	Good
	Firebase (FCM ,Real Database , Fire Store ,)	Current	+3	Moderate
	PHP (5,7,8) with Frameworks (Laravel)	Current	+5	Expert
ages	C#, ASP Net Core	2021	+1	Good
ngu	Node JS with Exprice	2020	+1	Good
s La	Oracle Apex 2019	2021	+1	Good
ltion	Python With Django	Current	1	Good
Web -Applications Languages	React	Current	1	Good
-Ap	Vue	Current	+2	Expert
Web	webpack , vite ,git	Current	34	Moderate
	jQuery, Type Script, JavaScript, Bootstrap, tailwind	Current	+5	Expert
S.	Microsoft Project	Current	+4	Moderate
forms	GitHub Platform	Current	+3	Expert
	Atlassian Jira Software development	Current	+2	Moderate
Tools Plat	azure DevOps	Current	+!	Good
T	Trello	Current	+1	Good
	Docker And Kubernetes Containers	Current	+1	Good
	Microsoft IIS	Current	+1	Good
ion	Xamp Server	2021	+4	Expert
Application Server	Laragon Server	Current	+2	Expert
App	Wamp server	2020	+3	Expert
	Tomcat	2021	+1	Moderate
S	Windows 2016/Server /Vista/Win7/Win8/Win10	Current	+10	Expert
So	Linux (Ubuntu)	Current	+3	Moderate